058-458-6484 (Israel) 201-994-6484 (US) ari.abramowitz1@gmail.com

# **Ari Abramowitz** Full Stack Web Developer

ariabr.netlify.app linkedin.com/in/ariabr github.com/ariabr

## **Summary**

Full stack web developer and software team lead experienced in both startup and agile environments. I am a creative and methodical problem solver with strong writing skills and a background in philosophy. I am always ready for a new challenge and the opportunity to bring another product to life.

## **Skills**

Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI

Backend / Databases: Python, Django, Flask, Node, Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Express, Firebase

Other Tools: Git, GitHub, Bash, Heroku, Jasmine, Pytest, Jira, Trello

## **Experience**

## Software Engineering Team Lead | Dynamic Healthcare Solutions

2023 - Present

- · Managed team of engineers in completing software projects
- · Contributed to the process of transforming business requirements into actionable tickets
- · Mentored team members on software development practices

#### Fullstack Software Engineer | Dynamic Healthcare Solutions

2020 - Present

- · Approved and deployed code across 15+ projects
- · Developed software to streamline AR management for 80,000+ residents in 80 facilities throughout the US
- · Improved efficiency of lab processing 2,000+ COVID tests per day by building an app to track sample history
- · Improved code quality by performing initial and final code reviews for a team of 10 developers
- · Wrote clear and detailed documentation to ease future development

### Software Developer | Taryag Analytics

2019 - 2020

- · Primary developer for a text mining and analytics startup
- Enabled 2020 Q1 beta launch by developing the frontend and backend for 6 new analysis features, including a sentence structure analyzer, a word cloud generator, and multiple text comparison tools
- · Improved comparative analysis capabilities by building a web-scraping ETL process to load new source data

#### **Powered by Sefaria Contest**

2020

- Frontend developer for team building a 3D family tree visualizer for the Powered by Sefaria contest
- · Awarded Honorable Mention and featured as a showcase project on the company's website

#### The Ezrat Nashim Database

2018 - Present

· Designed and developed crowdsourced website to aid users in assessing local synagogue options

## **Project Contributions**

| • | Supply Match (8,000+ users): Configured DB backups for site pairing donations with soldiers in need | 2023 |
|---|---|------|
|   | Django Easy Audit (6,000+ weekly downloads): Coded bug fix for database auditing package            | 2022 |
|   | Mindful Internet Use (1000+ users): Fixed frontend bug in Chrome productivity extension             | 2020 |

## **Education**

## **Continuing Education**

| · Bash Mastery: The Complete Guide to Bash Shell Scripting (Ziyad Yehia, Udemy)   | 2021 |
|---|------|
| · Test-Driven Development with Python (Harry Percival)  | 2021 |
| · The Ultimate Java Mastery Series (Code with Mosh)   | 2020 |
| Bloc   Web Developer Track  | 2019 |
| Della Tale and the second of the control of the second of |      |

- $\cdot\,\,$  Built 5 cloud-hosted web-apps as part of an 8-month apprentice-style coding bootcamp
- · Mastered fundamental principles of software engineering through project-based learning

## Rutgers University | BA | Summa Cum Laude | GPA: 3.94

2018

- · Majors: Philosophy, Jewish Studies; Minor: Religion
- · Semester Abroad: Honors Program, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem
- · Honor societies: Phi Beta Kappa; Natl. Society of Collegiate Scholars; Natl. Society of Leadership and Success